# **HEATHER SALVADOR**

(951) 906-9474 | hsalv001@gmail.com Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/heathersalvador/ | Website: www.smathaudhu.com/heather-salvador/

# = MECHANICAL ENGINEER =

Mechanical engineer and materials science engineer with five years of experience in the aerospace and manufacturing industry, including project management, working directly with key customers, and supervisory responsibilities. Five years as a researcher under the advisement of Dr. Suveen Mathaudhu, working in a research and development environment specific to experimental design, scientific evaluation, and science communication relating to processing-property relationships in structural metals.

# ———— CAREER HIGHLIGHTS —

#### **RESEARCH**

- Put systems in place to manage lab organization, cleanliness, ordering of consumables, and student notes
- Coordinated research collaboration with members at Sandia National Laboratories
- Presented research results at multiple national and international conferences

#### **INDUSTRY**

- Spearheaded development of an assembly and test facility with trained lab technicians for a new product line
- Build and test of a development valve for the Boeing Space Launch System propulsion system

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

RESEARCHER Riverside, CA

UC Riverside, Mathaudhu Lab

June 2016 - present

- Conduct background science and previous research reviews relevant to each project
- Designed experiments with the goal of expanding scientific knowledge
- Present key research results, publish results in scientific journals
- Mentor undergraduate students in scientific thinking and experimental design

### MANUFACTURING SUPERVISOR

South El Monte, CA

VACCO Industries

*June 2014 – April 2016* 

- Oversaw and participated in the design and build of an assembly and test facility for space launch valve production.
- Responsible for hiring and training cleanroom-level technicians.
- Initiated cross-team collaboration and management to ensure on-time production.

#### PROJECT ENGINEER

South El Monte, CA

VACCO Industries

June 2012 – June 2014

- Managed the design development and testing of a space launch system valve
- Prepared and reviewed manufacturing paperwork and test procedures
- Facilitated seamless transfer to production for delivery according to a customer-set schedule.

## **QUALITY ENGINEER INTERN**

Santa Ana, CA

GKN Aerospace

June 2011 – December 2011

- Audited manufacturing paperwork for consistency and completion
- Tracked and moved open quality incidents to closure
- Worked with inspectors to standardize and improve inspection processes. Key achievements include the development of a standardized inspection instruction with accompanying visual work instruction

EDUCATION —

### PH.D. MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Riverside, CA

University of California, Riverside

June 2016 – July 2021 (estimated)

**B.S.+M.S. MECHANICAL ENGINEERING** 

Riverside, CA

University of California, Riverside

June 2007 – June 2012